Guide to the Elaine D. Engst papers, 1979-2015.
Engst, Elaine D. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Elaine D. Engst papers, 1979-2015.
13-6-4088
Engst, Elaine D.
10.3 cubic feet.
Correspondence, publications, printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Professional papers, including alphabetical subject files and files relating to other professional activities.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Elaine D.Engst came to the Cornell University Library in 1979, and has served as Assistant Director of the New York Historical Resources Center, with primary responsibilities for managing the Historical Documents Inventory. She also served as Technical Services Archivist in the Department of Manuscripts and University Archives (1983-1992), as Curator of Manuscripts in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections (1992-1995); as University Archivist (1995-present), as Associate Director for RMC (1997-1999), and as Director of RMC (1999-2013). She has served on numerous Cornell Library committees. She has also been professionally active, in the Society of American Archivists, where she served on and chaired the Standards Committee and the Program Committee, as well as the SAA Council. She has also served on and chaired the New York State Historical Records Advisory Board (2002- ). For her work on the HDI, in 1991, she was awarded SAA's C.W.F. Coker Prize for outstanding finding aids. In 1996, for her professional accomplishments, she was named a Fellow of the Society of American Archivists.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Professional papers, including alphabetical subject files and files relating to other professional activities.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Engst, Elaine D.; Cornell University -- Archives.; Cornell University Library. Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections.; Cornell University Library.; Cornell University. Department of Manuscripts and University Archives.; Society of American Archivists.
Subjects:
Archivists.; Women archivists.; Archives -- New York (State) -- Ithaca.; Archives -- United States.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted to permission of the donor.
CONTAINER LIST
- American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences (AAFCS) Project Archivist Employment, 2004-2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences (AAFCS) Archival Consultant Report, 1988, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- The Academy of Natural Sciences' John Gould Exhibit, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Accessioning Guidelines and Flowcharts, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "Documenting Post-War Activist Science" Meeting, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- African-American History at Cornell University
  - African-American Collections at Cornell University, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cornell University Black History (Ellen DuBois Essay) from Professor Margaret Rossiter, 1986, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Early African-American Students at Cornell University (Related Newspaper Articles and Collections) (Includes photocopies), 1898-1990, 2003-2007 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Alpha Phi Alpha Centennial Exhibit, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Martin Luther King at Cornell University, 1960, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Class Book Pictures of Early African-American Students at Cornell University (Includes photocopies), 1897-1918, 1931, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Includes 3 CDs
- Agricultural History Society Symposium, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Arthur A. Allen Collection
  - David G. Allen Donation, 1969, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Final Version of the Arthur A. Allen Collection Guide, 1980, 1985, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Draft of the Arthur A. Allen Collection Guide, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Possible DH for Arthur A. Allen Collection Guide, [n.d.] (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Deceased Alumni Files Proposal, 1987, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Cornell Alumni Federation/Association Speeches
  - Cornell Alumni Federation Speaker Series, 2001-2004, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 19-25)
  - Cornell Club of Northeastern Ohio Talk, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Includes 1 CD
  - Cornell Women's Club of Syracuse Talk, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Includes 2 CDs
- American Artistic Renaissance Symposium, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Ithaca Journal Articles on Cornell University's 125th Anniversary, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- 125th Anniversary/Reunion Celebrations at Barton Hall, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 30-32)
- The Samuel J. May Anti-Slavery Collection
  - Reports on the Conservation and Digitization of Anti-Slavery Pamphlets, 1999-2003 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Photocopy of the Accession Letter for the Samuel J. May Collection, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - South Central Research Library Council (SCRLC) Grant Application for the Samuel J. May Anti-Slavery Collection, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- "Cornell Architecture, Arts and Planning: 125 Years of Achievement" Exhibit
  - Organization of Cornell Architecture, Arts and Planning (AAP) Items for the "125 Years of Achievement" Exhibit, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Secondary Sources for the Organization of the "125 Years of Achievement" Exhibit, 1911-1913, 1942, 1979, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 37-39)
  - Cornell College of Architecture Newsletters and "125 Years of Achievement" Exhibit Donors (Includes photocopies), 1899, 1947, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Guides and Publications on Architecture Archives, 1984, 1985, 1987-1988, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Letter to Richard Meier on the Michael A. McCarthy Records and an Architecture Archive, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Archives and Computers: A Symposium for the Uninitiated at the Rockefeller Archive Center, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Arecibo Observatory Archives Statement of Purpose, 2001, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Academic Research Libraries (ARL)
  - Academic Research Libraries (ARL) Special Collections Survey, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Academic Research Libraries (ARL) Special Collections Symposium (and ARL Task Force), 2001, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Academic Research Libraries (ARL) Security Survey, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Address Resolution Protocol (ARP) Information and Data Preparation Instructions, 1980, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Peter Hirtle on ARTstor Download Restrictions, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Cornell East Asia Program Student Project, 2006, 2008, 2010, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- "Liberty Hyde Bailey: A Man for All Seasons" Exhibit
  - Conservation and Processing Work on the Liberty Hyde Bailey Papers, 1984, 1993, 1996, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Grant Application for Processing the Liberty Hyde Bailey Papers (and Forthcoming Exhibit), 2001, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Secondary Sources for the Organization of the Liberty Hyde Bailey Exhibit, 1952, 1990, 1996, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Review of Liberty Hyde Bailey Papers, [n.d.] (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Case Descriptions for the Liberty Hyde Bailey Exhibit, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Baldwin Cornerstone Re-Installation Ceremony, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- "Beautiful Birds: Masterpieces from the Hill Ornithology Collection" Exhibit, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- "The Cornell Tradition: Freedom and Responsibility," by Carl L. Becker, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- The American Heritage Virtual Digital Archive Project (or, the Berkeley Project), 1995 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Hans Bethe Papers
  - Correspondence from and Concerning the Hans Bethe Papers with Collection Description Draft, 1936, 1937, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Photographs of the Hans Bethe Exhibit, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Lists of Items Borrowed for and Diagrams Mapping the Hans Bethe Exhibit, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Processing Proposal and Final Report for the Hans Bethe Papers, 2007, 2009, 2010-2011 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Correspondence on Processing the Hans Bethe Papers, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Paul Betz's "William Wordsworth and the Romantic Imagination: A Scholar’s Collection" Exhibit, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Correspondence on the Permanent Loan of the Blaschka Models to the Corning Museum of Glass, 1963, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Harold Bloom's Visit to Cornell, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- A Book of Views Donation, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Correspondence with Mia Boynton on Louis Agassiz Fuertes Collection, 1997-1999, 2004, 2013-2014 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Joyce Brothers Papers, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Joan Jacobs Brumberg and the Adolescent Diary Project, 1990, 1992-1993, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Cornell Buildings Data Project
  - Cornell Buildings Data Project Meeting Summaries and Grant Proposal, 2002, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Facilities Archival Records, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Digitization of Cornell University Building Plans, 2000, 2002, 2005, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Records Management Concerns with Storage of Cornell Building Plans, 1963, 1991, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Cornell Association of Class Officers (CACO) (and Cornell University 125th Anniversary Celebrations)
  - 125th Anniversary Celebration in San Francisco, California, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Organization of 125th Anniversary Exhibit with Item Lists and Schedules, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cornell Association of Class Officers' Midwinter Meeting in New York City, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
- Campus Club Information Pamphlets and Anna Botsford Comstock Talk, 1929, 1951, 1975, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Repossession of the Carrier Corporation Records, 1965, 1977, 1987, 1989-1990, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Carrier Corporation Microfilming Project, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Child Pornography Laws (on the Purchase of the Paidikion), 1982, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Workshop on Archiving and Preservation with Shanghai Municipal Archives Delegation, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Collections Relating to City and Regional Planning, 2007, 2010, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Annotated Bibliography of Historic City Plans and Views (1493-1802) Exhibit, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Clarke and Rapuano Records, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Class of 1932 Reunion Talk, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Grant Application to the Council on Library and Information Resources (CLIR) for the Paleontological Research Institution (PRI) Archives, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Grant Application to the Council on Library and Information Resources (CLIR) for "Documenting the Family and Social Change in New York: A Collaborative Approach", 2009-2010 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Correspondence on the Cornell Cold Fusion Archive and its Early Finding Aid, 1989, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
- University Policy on the Confidentiality of Student Records, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Anna Botsford Comstock Presentation at the DeWitt Historical Society of Tompkins County, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Howard Conklin Papers (and F.F. Hill Memorial Proposal), 1982, 1988, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Letter and Item List for Comstock Hall Exhibit on John Henry and Anna Botsford Comstock, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Grant Application for the Preservation of the Constance (Connie) Eberhardt Cook Papers, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Constance (Connie) Eberhardt Cook Papers Project Drafts and Correspondence, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- J. Robert (Bob) Cooke's Project on W. Keith Kennedy and Other Oral History Interviews, 1966, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Conservation Department Guidelines and Miscellany, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Archival Scanning Project Proposal, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Exchanges between the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections and the Conservation Department, 1990, 1992-1994, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Use of Research Libraries Information Network (RLIN) for Preservation Microfilming and Notation in "Field 583", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Ezra Cornell Letters and Exhibits
  - Ezra Cornell Miscellany, 1996, 1999, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Donation of Ezra Cornell's Battle at Bull Run Letter (Includes photocopies), 1861, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Ezra Cornell's Letter to His Granddaughter (Photocopies), 1867 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Two Letters from Ezra Cornell (Photocopies), 1869-1870 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Programs for the Ezra Cornell Bicentennial Celebrations, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Histories and Case Descriptions for the "Invention and Enterprise: Ezra Cornell, a Nineteenth-Century Life" Exhibit, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Ezra Cornell Scanning Project (Includes photocopies), 1844, 1854, 1873-1874, 1969, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 36-37)
- Cornell University Miscellany
  - Lists of Cornell University Administration, 1947-1992 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Two (19th Century) Articles on the Construction of Cornell University (Photocopies), 1866, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - "The Football Season of 1897" from the Cornell Era; and, a Newspaper Clipping on the Origin of Campbell's Soup's Colors (Includes photocopies), 1897, [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Cornell, Wisconsin, and Cornell College Name Origins, 1948, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Cornell 101 Course, 1990, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Policy on Scanning the Cornell Daily Sun, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Cornell Daily Sun Digitization Project, 1962-1964, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Cornell Beer Steins and Other Cornell Memorabilia, 1976, 2008-2009 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - "Cornell '69: A Retrospective" from The Bookpress: The Newspaper of the Literary Arts, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Examples of Cornell University Seals (Includes photocopies), 1874, 1990, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous Cornell University Library Histories and Chronologies, 1951, 1955, 1973, 1995, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 48-49)
  - Invitations and Programs to Miscellaneous Lectures and Events, 2003, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- The Correspondence University at Ithaca, New York (Includes photocopies), 1883, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Proposal to Process the Dale R. Corson Papers, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Cornell Costume and Textile Collection Online Access, c. 2008 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- New Cornell Letterhead Logo, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Cuneiform and "Introduction to the Cornell Tablet Collection," by David I. Owen, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Correspondence with Peter Curtiss and Cornelliana Donations, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- The Curtiss-Wright Engineering Cadette Program, 1942-1943, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Cryptology and "Charles J. Mendelsohn and Why I Envy Him," by David Kahn, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Dante and Petrarch Microfilming and Access Project, 1974, 1997, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- The Divine Comedy Image Archive, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Patty Elwin Davis Quilt, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Deceased Alumni Records Accessibility, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Cornell University Digital Access Coalition (DAC) Minutes and Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Digital Imaging Workshops and Guides, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 64-66)
- Digital Image Collections Inventory Surveys, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 67-68)
- Image Management and Access Group at Cornell University (IMAG/CU) Request for Proposal (RFP), 1996 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Farewell Songs for Mark Dimunation, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 70)
- Transfer of Mayor David Dinkins' Campaign Material to Columbia University, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 71)
- Quote from The Cornellian on "Distance Learning" (Includes photocopies), 1879, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 72)
- Documentation Newsletter for the 125th Anniversary Celebrations (Includes photocopies), 1862, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  Includes a Floppy Disk Entitled: "125 Exhibit Files"
- Documentation Newsletter for the Biology and Society Major (in Conjunction with the Collections on the History of Medicine and Health Planning), 1970, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 74-75)
  Includes a Floppy Disk Entitled: "HSC Publicity meddescr"
- Identifying and Cataloging Chinese Artwork, 1990, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 76)
- Donald A. Downs' Oral History Project on the Robertson Committee Documents, 1969, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 77)
- Niels A. Douwes Dekker Exhibit, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 78)
- Corey Earle's Cornelliana Lists and Chronologies, [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 79)
- List of Early American and New York History Manuscript Collections, c. 1995 (Box 2, Folder 80)
- "History of the Department of Economics at Cornell," by Annemie Maertens, c. 2010 (Box 2, Folder 81)
- Sarah Elbert's Research on the Alcotts and Samuel J. May, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 82)
- The John M. Echols Southeast Asia Collection
  - "Javanese Literature in Surakarta Manuscripts," by Nancy K. Florida, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Acquisition of the Gaston Liébert Papers, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Acquisition of the Balinese Manuscript Project, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Southeast Asia (Echols) Collection Projects, 1989, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 86)
- Electronic Records Guidelines and Projects
  - Project 2000 Reports, 1997, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 87-88)
  - Electronic Records Data Access Policy 4.8, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Retention of Records Policy and Guidelines, 1987, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - National Historical Publications and Records Commission (NHPRC) Grant Application for the Archival Electronic Records Practice Project, 1991, 1995, 1997-2000 (Box 3, Folder 2-4)
  - Archival Electronic Records Practice Project Reports, 1997-1999 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Electronic Student Records Systems (ESRS) Project, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
  - "Working Together" Workshop for Archivists, Records Managers and Information Technologists, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Work Plans for the Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Project, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - e-Cornell Brochure, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Electronic Theses and Dissertations (ETD) Project and DAISY Project, 1998-1999, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
- Miscellaneous Exhibit Planning and Prospectives, 1989-1992, 1994, 1999, 2002, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 14-17)
- Exhibit Case Designs, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- C. Herbert Finch Memorial Service, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
  Includes a Color Photograph of C. Herbert Finch and a CD of the Funeral Program
- First Year Family Weekend Committee, 2002, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Organization of "The Passionate Collector: Willard Fiske and His Libraries" Exhibit, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Willard Fiske's Last Will, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Letter from Cornell President Jacob Gould Schurman to Charles Sidney Shepard on Willard Fiske's Last Will, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Correspondence with Robert Foote on Oral History Interviews, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- John Colin Forbes Bibliographic References, 1900, 1967, 1997, 1999, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Early Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections Work Forms
  - Miscellaneous Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections Forms, c. 1994 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections Donation and Memorandum of Understanding Forms, [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections Work Sheets, [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections Paging and Photocopying Request Form and Guideline Drafts, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections Deaccessioning Forms, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- List of College of Agriculture and Life Sciences and New York Agriculture Oral History Interviews, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Finding Aid for the Jane M. G. Foster Papers, 1978, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- The French Revolution Collection Projects
  - Drafts of the Jon Lindseth Proposal for the French Revolution Research Libraries Information Network (RLIN) Records Project and Correspondence with Professor Nan E. Karwan, 1987, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 34-35)
  - Drafts of the Jon Lindseth Proposal for the French Revolution Pamphlet Project, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 36-37)
  - Guide to the Research Libraries Information Network (RLIN) Records for the French Revolution Collection, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 38-39)
  - Supplementary Guide to the Research Libraries Information Network (RLIN) Records for the French Revolution Collection for Library Staff, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Three Part Report of the Retrospective Conversion and Preservation Project of the French Revolution Collection, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Collaboration between the Frick Art Reference Library and the Cornell University Library Archives, 1997-1999 (Box 3, Folder 42-43)
- The Louis Agassiz Fuertes Collection
  - Bibliography of Louis Agassiz Fuertes' Illustrations and Publications, [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Bibliographic and Taxonomic Identification Abbreviations (and Additional Louis Agassiz Fuertes Miscellany), 1926, 1933, [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Processing Report and Listing of Series I (Correspondence) of the Louis Agassiz Fuertes Papers, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Organization for the Electronic Version of the "Of a Feather: Audubon and Fuertes" Exhibit and the Kodak Library Image Consortium (KLIC) Collaboration, 1987, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 47-48)
  - Selected Louis Agassiz Fuertes Letters (Includes photocopies), c. 1898-1927 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    Includes 12 Photograph Reproductions on Film Slides
  - Condition and Treatment Report for the Louis Agassiz Fuertes Preservation Project, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Box Listing for Louis Agassiz Fuertes' Artwork, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 51-52)
    Folder 3-51 Includes a Floppy Disk Entitled: "Fuertes Lists"
  - Finding Aid Lists of Louis Agassiz Fuertes' Paintings to be Digitized, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 53-54)
  - Exhibit Cards for Louis Agassiz Fuertes Exhibit, [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Notes on Data Entry and Tag Structures for the Louis Agassiz Fuertes Papers, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 56-57)
  - Archival Locations and Drawer Arrangements for Louis Agassiz Fuertes' Artwork, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Transparency Reproduction Orders and Correspondence, 1978-1979, 1981, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Louis Agassiz Fuertes' Photography Processing Notes and Procedures, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - The Harriman Alaska Expedition Journal for the Louis Agassiz Fuertes Image Database, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Budget and Proposed Finding Aid for the Frank Ernest Gannett and Caroline Werner Gannett Papers, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Letter on the Gee Family Papers, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Budget and Processing Reports for the Rose K. Goldsen Collection, 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- The Rose Goldsen Archive of New Media Art Miscellany, 2003-2004, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Grant Application to the Digital Heritage Initiative from the Daniel Langlois Foundation for the Rose Goldsen Archive for New Media Art, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- "Green Dragons and Big Red Bears: Cornell History and Traditions" Presentation, 2002, 2004, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
- Fifty-Nine Film Slides for the "Green Dragons and Big Red Bears: Cornell History and Traditions" Presentation, c. 2002 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- "Green Dragons and Big Red Bears: Cornell History and Traditions" Script for the WCNY "Unique New York" Segment, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Letters to George William Harris Regarding "Dishonest" Book Agents (Includes photocopies), 1893-1894 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Charles Frederick Hartt Papers and a Biographical Article, 1999, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- "Hidden" Artifact Collections at Cornell University
  - Cornell University "Classical" or "Hidden" Collections (Includes photocopies), 1871, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Student Essays for History 126 on Hidden Treasure Archive Locations, 1955, 1999, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
  - "A Compendium of Research and Historical Artifact Collections at Cornell University," by Francis C. Moon; and, "Skeletons in the Closet," an Inventory Project Proposal, 2002, 2008-2010 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
  - Articles and Bibliographic Listings of Hidden Collections, 1930, 1978, 2002-2004 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence with Elizabeth Baker Wells and Other Miscellaneous Information on "Catalogue of Art Works at Cornell University" (Includes photocopies), 1885, 1911, 1948, 1968, 1970, 1973, 1975, 1976-1977, 1979, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)